Johnny Otis Collection, 1949-2012 SC 106
Archives of African American Music and Culture
Johnny Otis Collection
1949-2012
Archives of African American Music and Culture
Otis, Johnny, 1921-2012
SC 106
1 records carton
310 photographs
753 Audiotape Reels analog: 5, 7, and 10 in.
3 Videocassettes VHS
5 Videocassettes MDV
2 Audiocassettes DAT
77 Audiocassettes analog
1 digital audio files
Approximately 800 radio aircheck tapes of radio programs of black popular music (live and prerecorded), hosted by Johnny Otis, and featuring live interviews with blues and rhythm & blues artists from the 1940s, 1950s, and 1960s. Artists interviewed include Little Esther Phillips, Al Frazier, Mary Wells, Zola Taylor, the Coasters, Horace Silver, the Robins, Etta James, Big Jay McNeely, Bobby Day, Bumps Blackwell, Pee Wee Crayton, Jimmy McCracklin, and Joe Liggins. Also included are photographs, memorabilia, books, and compact discs.
Arrangement
Arranged in six series:
Series 1: Personal papers
Series 2: Writings
Series 3: Radio program cue sheets
Series 4: Radio Airchecks, Johnny Otis Show
--- Sub-Series 4.1: KPPC-AM (Pasadena, Calif.)
--- Sub-Series 4.2: KPFK (Los Angeles) and KPFA (Berkeley)
Series 5: Time-based Media
Series 6: Photographs
Biographical / Historical
Johnny Otis, known as the "Godfather of R&B," was born in 1921 to Greek immigrants in Vallejo, California. Two years later his family moved to a predominantly Black neighborhood in Berkeley, where his father opened a grocery store. In this environment, Otis experienced and internalized Black culture from an early age and was particularly influenced by African American music styles. In high school he learned to play the drums and in 1940 landed his first professional job with Count Otis Matthew's West Oakland House Rockers. The following year he began playing and touring with Black territory big bands led by musicians such as George Morrison and Lloyd Hunter. After settling in Los Angeles, Otis became a session drummer for jazz greats such as Lester Young and performed and recorded with his own big band, scoring his first hit with an arrangement of "Harlem Nocturne" in 1946.
As the demand for big bands waned, Otis downsized to a combo, forging a new style that became known as rhythm and blues. Over the next decade he played an important role in the development of rhythm and blues, discovering, producing, promoting and performing with artists such as Little Esther Phillips, The Robins, The Coasters, Mel Walker, Etta James, Jackie Wilson, Big Mama Thornton, Little Willie John, and Hank Ballard. Otis led the house bands at Club Alabam on Central Avenue and the Barrelhouse, a nightclub he opened in Watts, and toured extensively with his popular live revue show. During this period Otis also released a string of hit records including "Willie and the Hand Jive," wrote songs for other artists, served as a record label talent scout, and operated a recording studio, record shop and the Dig Records label.
In 1954 Otis began his media career as host of "The Johnny Otis Show," a rhythm and blues radio program which he adapted into a weekly television series that aired on KTTV from 1955-1961 and was briefly revived in the 1970s. The popularity of Otis's radio show persisted over several decades, continually introducing new audiences to the many African American artists he worked with throughout his career, highlighting their achievements, and addressing issues such as systemic racism within the industry. Otis also ventured into print media in 1960, writing a column for the Sentinel, one of L.A.'s leading Black newspapers, which he used as a platform to address racial equality and social justice.
Otis was voted into the Rock & Roll Hall of Fame in 1994 and received a Pioneer Award from the Rhythm & Blues Foundation for his role in the development of these styles. In addition to his musical career, Otis was an avid painter and sculptor, author, ordained minister, organic farmer, and civil rights activist. He founded the Landmark Community Church in the late 1970s and advocated tirelessly for the homeless, organizing food drives such as the Red Beans and Rice Festivals promoted on his radio shows. He married Phyllis Walker, an Afro-Filipina woman, in 1941 and had several children. Otis frequently performed with his sons, guitarist Shuggie Otis and drummer Nicky Otis, and in later years with grandson Lucky Otis on bass. Johnny Otis died in 2012 at the age of 90.
Access Restrictions
Use of time-based media materials (audio and video) may require production of listening or viewing copies.
Access to streaming audio, moving image, and full resolution digital image materials may currently be restricted to researchers who can authenticate with an IU account or who are physically present on campus. Remote streaming to individual researchers may be allowed with the completion of applicable forms.
For further information about access to online audiovisual materials, contact AAAMC staff at aaamc@indiana.edu.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Johnny Otis in 1990 with regular accretions through 1995; additional accretions donated via Portia K. Maultsby and Terry Gould.
Custodial History
The Johnny Otis Show aircheck tapes were originally deposited at the IU Archives of Traditional in 1990; custody was transferred to the Archives of African American Music and Culture in 1997 and 2022.
Related Materials
Some additional programs held by Pacifica Radio Archives.
Also see the archival collection at the AAAMC: Johnny Otis and Bill Griffith Video Collection (SC 100).
Scope and Contents
This collection includes materials created during Johnny Otis's career as a musician, artist, writer, minister, civil rights activist and radio deejay. Personal papers consist primarily of articles, biographical information, programs and press clippings from 1949-2012. Writings include copies of Otis's L.A. Sentinel column "Let's Talk" from 1960-1964, an undated article on rhythm and blues music and books published from 1993-2009. Photographs span the years from 1940-1994 and feature portraits of Otis with many notable rhythm and blues artists, candid photos taken during camping and hunting trips, family portraits, and performances at various venues including the Barrelhouse and the Hollywood jazz club Shelly's Manne-Hole. Other images capture Otis in radio, television and recording studios and his participation in political activities.
The bulk of the collection documents "The Johnny Otis Show" radio programs through recorded airchecks, original handwritten cue sheets and tape logs compiled at Indiana University. The weekly radio programs are divided into two subseries, beginning with Otis's "Blue Monday" edition broadcast over KPPC-AM (Pasadena) from 1970-1972. In addition to playing the music of blues and rhythm and blues artists, the shows feature interviews and live performance segments by artists ranging from Freddy King, Joe Liggins and Frank Zappa to Shuggie and Nicky Otis. The majority of the airchecks are from the second subseries, broadcast from 1982-1994 over public radio stations KPFK (Los Angeles) and KPFA (Berkeley) and syndicated by Pacifica. These programs frequently include musical guests from the glory days of rhythm and blues as well as call-ins from radio listeners, while other programs follow the standard deejay hosted format with Otis introducing R&B, jazz and gospel records and publicizing local events. In 1993, Otis opened the Johnny Otis Market and Cabaret in Sebastopol where he broadcast his show live, often featuring members of his band. The most notable live broadcasts were recorded at the Monterey Jazz Festival in 1984 and Chicago Blues Festival in 1993; other shows were broadcast live from hotels where Otis was performing with his band.
Other time-based media in the collection includes Otis's appearance at the 1998 Society for Ethnomusicology conference at Indiana University, Bloomington, where he participated in an interview, forum, and performed at the closing concert with the IU Soul Revue.
Rhythm and blues music; Radio airchecks
- 1. Personal papers, 1949-2012, undated; 21 Folders
  - Advertisement for Mennen foam shave (art by Opal Louis Nations), 2005-06-03; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical timeline (handwritten), undated; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Biographies, 1998-2001, undated; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Biographies and press packet, 1983-1991; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Blues Beat (Sonoma County Blues Society Newsletter), 1994 February-March; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Brochure, The Johnny Otis Show, 1975?; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Campaign brochure, Assemblyman 63rd District, CA, 1962?; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1949-1960; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, 1980-1989; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Clipping, "Around L.A. in the 1950s", 1983; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Clipping, Jack the Rapper newsletter, 1982-04-14; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Clippings (original), 1980-1995; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Clippings and articles, Bloomington, IN, 1998; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1990-1999; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, Pacific Sun, 1997; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence (with Otis cartoon), 1993-1997; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Cream magazine (R. Crumb cover), "Doin' That Hand Jive with his Feet," by John Morthland (p. 46-53), Vol. 3, No. 6, 1971-11; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Funeral program and obituary, Johnny Otis, 2012; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Press release, Watts Towers Jazz Festival, 1983-07-07; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Publicity, Otis at SEM Conference, IU, 1998; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Spirit of the Black Territory Bands, 1992?; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 21)
- 2. Writings, 1960-2009, undated; 5 books; 6 Folders
  - Book, Colors and Chords: The Art of Johnny Otis (Book), 1995; 1 book (Box 1)
  - Book, Colors and Chords: The Art of Johnny Otis (promotional brochure, 16 p.), 1995; 1 book (Box 1)
  - Book, Red Beans & Rice and other Rock 'n' Roll Recipes, 1997; 1 book (Box 1)
  - Book, Upside Your Head! Rhythm and Blues on Central Avenue, 1993; 1 book (Box 1)
  - Book, Listen to the Lambs, 2009; 1 book (Box 1)
  - Column, Let's Talk, L.A. Sentinel (photocopies), 1960; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Column, Let's Talk, L.A. Sentinel (photocopies), 1961; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Column, Let's Talk, L.A. Sentinel (photocopies), 1962; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Column, Let's Talk, L.A. Sentinel (photocopies), 1963; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Column, Let's Talk, L.A. Sentinel (photocopies), 1964; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Rhythm and Blues (32 typed leaves), undated; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 27)
- 3. Radio program cue sheets, 1970-1995; 22 Folders
  - Cue Sheets (handwritten), 1975-1976; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Cue Sheets, programs 66-100 (typed), 1983-1984; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Cue Sheets (handwritten), 1986; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Cue Sheets (handwritten), 1987; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Cue Sheets (handwritten), 1992; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Cue Sheets (handwritten), 1993; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Cue Sheets (handwritten), 1994; 1 Folder (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - IU Tape Logs, 1970-1995; 15 Folders (Box 1, Folders 35-49)
- 4. Radio Airchecks, Johnny Otis Show
  - 4.1. KPPC-AM (Pasadena, Calif.), 1970-1972
    - Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, 1970-08-03; 1 Audiotape Reel 7 in.; Featured guest(s): Pee Wee Crayton, Shuggie Otis
      Shelf Number
      EC 12903
      Online Access
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/q18257cz3h
      Scope and Contents
      Blue Monday episode with live performance segments featuring Johnny Otis with Pee Wee Crayton and Shuggie Otis. J. Otis and Crayton discuss Crayton's Fender guitar, built by Leo Fender himself. Crayton and S. Otis perform "Blues After Hours," "Adrian's Boogie" (also known as "Peach's Boogie"), "Slow Blues in G" (some distortion), and "Green Bay."
    - Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, 1970-08-17; 1 Audiotape Reel 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Eddie Ray, Joe Liggins
      EC10 3657
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/h73p88k10g
      Otis plays the music of Fats Domino, Soul Stirrers, Son Jackson, Archibald, Ernie Freeman, Fats Domino, Charles Brown, Smiley Lewis, Lightnin' Hopkins, Snookey, and The Jewels. Live performance by Joe Liggins. Otis and Eddie Ray talk about the song "Blueberry Hill," the old days of rock 'n' roll, Texas bluesmen, Smiley Lewis, and Imperial Records reissues.
    - Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, 1970-08-24; 1 Audiotape Reel 7 in.; Featured guest(s): Freddy King, Shuggie Otis, Soupe Bradshaw, Nicky Otis
      EC 12901
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/q97781zh99
      Live performance segments featuring Johnny Otis with Freddy King, Shuggie Otis, Soup Bradshaw, and Nicky Otis. King, Bradshaw and S. Otis perform "Little Shuffle in C" and an unidentified slow blues tune. J. Otis and King discuss King's origins and influences and the origin of the riff from "San Jose."
    - Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, 1970-09-14; 1 Audiotape Reel 7 in.; Featured guest(s): Model T Slim, Shuggie Otis
      EC 12907
      Live performance segments featuring Johnny Otis with Model T Slim and Shuggie Otis. J. Otis and Slim discuss Slim's three names. Shuggie Otis and Slim perform "Somebody Hoodooed the Hoodoo Man" (some print-through). Shuggie Otis and Slim perform "Oh Baby, You're Gonna Miss Me When I'm Gone" (some print-through).
    - Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, 1970-09-21; 1 Audiotape Reel 7 in.; Featured guest(s): Frank "Honeyboy" Patt, Shuggie Otis
      EC 12904
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/c289507060
      Live performance segments featuring Johnny Otis with Frank "Honeyboy" Patt and Shuggie Otis performing "I Got a Right to Love My Baby." J. Otis talks to Pat about his nickname "Honeyboy," Patt and Shuggie perform an unidentified slow blues tune, and Shuggie performs "Honeyboy's Blues."
    - Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, 1970-09-28; 1 Audiotape Reel 7 in.; Featured guest(s): Gus Jenkins, Shuggie Otis
      EC 12909
      Live performance segments featuring Johnny Otis with Gus Jenkins and Shuggie Otis. Shuggie Otis and Jenkins perform unidentified uptempo blues and slow blues song, and Shuggie ad libs "Picture Frame Boogie."
    - Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, 1970-10-05; 1 Audiotape Reel 7 in.; Featured guest(s): Phillip Walker, Shuggie Otis
      EC 12910
      Live performance segments featuring Johnny Otis with Phillip Walker and Shuggie Otis. J. Otis and Walker discuss Walker's hometown. Walker and Shuggie perform "You've Lost Your Good Thing Now," "Phillip's Boogie" (instrumental), and "Bad Luck is Fallin'." J. Otis and Walker discuss the origins of "Trouble In My Home" and Walker's influences, their favorite cities for touring, and experiences on the road. Otis tells stories of daughter's birth while on tour and an on-stage goof.
    - Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, 1970-10-19; 1 Audiotape Reel 7 in.; Featured guest(s): Guitar Slim Green, Shuggie Otis, Roy Milton
      EC 12908
      Live performance segments featuring Slim Green. Johnny Otis with Slim Green, Shuggie Otis, and Roy Milton. J. Otis and Green discuss Green's new album, Green's early life, his first gig with Otis, and the song "Old Folks Boogie." Shuggie and Green perform unidentified song. J. Otis and Green discuss Green's first recordings and the song "Make Love All Night." Green performs an unidentified song.
    - Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, 1970-11-02; 2 Audiotape Reels 7 in.; Featured guest(s): Frank Zappa, Shuggie Otis, Ray Agee, Wilbur Reynolds, Mrs. John Fulbright
      EC10 3668; EC10 2525
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/138j435k1s
      Tape 1 (EC10" 3668): Otis plays the music of "Guitar" Slim Green, Roy Milton, and Frank Zappa. Live performances by Zappa, Agee, and Shuggie. Zappa tells how the first 45 record he stole was by Agee; Agee and Otis talk about some of Agee's records. Otis welcomes Wilbur Reynolds and Mrs. John Fulbright to the show.
      Tape 2 (EC 10" 2525): Otis plays the music of The Mothers of Invention, Cleave Duncan & The Penguins, Ray Agee, Wilbur Reynolds & The Soul Finders, Screamin' Jay Hawkins, Bo Carter, Ray Charles, Doves, Otis & Delmar "Mighty Mouth" Evans, Ike & Tina Turner, and Johnny Otis. Live performance by Frank Zappa and Shuggie Otis. Otis talks to Zappa about writing "Memories of Almonty" and "Every Time I See You," the Almonty Legion Stadium and the town of Almonty.
    - Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, 1970-11-09; 1 Audiotape Reel 7 in.; Featured guest(s): Johnny Shines, Shuggie Otis
      EC 12905
      Live performance segments featuring Johnny Shines. Johnny Otis with Jonny Shines and Shuggie Otis. Heavy distortion throughout tape. J. Otis and Shines talk about the roots of blues, Memphis blues, Chicago blues, R&B. S. Otis and Shines perform an unidentified Delta blues. J. Otis and Shines discuss Shines' Alabama home and the blues revival. S. Otis and Shines perform an unidentified gutbucket-style blues and unidentified boogie blues. J. Otis and Shines talk about Robert Johnson. Shines perform "Crossroads" in Robert Johnson's style.
    - Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, 1970-12-14; 1 Audiotape Reel 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Freddy King, Richard Berry, Shuggie Otis
      EC 12902
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/p58p38zj6t
      Blue Monday episode with live performance segments featuring Johnny Otis with Freddy King, Shuggie Otis, Michael Franklin, Mimi Simos, and Richard Berry. J. Otis and King discuss the origins of "Have You Ever Loved a Woman?"; Franklin and Simos offer a tarot card reading; J. Otis and Berry discuss Berry's early music experiences, his connection to "Roll With Me Henry," the origins of "Louie Louie," and "No Room" and its rhythmic style. Content ends abruptly at end of reel.
    - Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, 1971-01-25; 1 Audiotape Reel 7 in.; Featured guest(s): Shakey Jake, Shuggie Otis
      EC 12906
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/q77f75tg1x
      Blue Monday episode with live performance segments featuring Shakey Jake and Shuggie Otis. S. Jake and S. Otis perform "Call Me If You Need Me." S. Otis performs original boogie guitar piece, "Dedicated to Shakey Jake." J. Otis plays record "Shake's Blues" and they discuss session personnel.
    - Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, 1971-02-22; 2 Audiotape Reels 7 in.; Featured guest(s): Buddy Guy, Junior Wells, Johnny Shines, Shuggie Otis
      EC 12911; EC 12912
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/j43009z443
      Tape 1: J. Otis and Buddy Guy discuss rehearsing and musical spontaneity. Guy and Junior Wells perform "Mannish Boy" and unidentified song. Otis and Guy discuss the lack of blues on radio, tell stories about audience reception, Guy meeting Jimi Hendrix, Lester Young and other influences including B.B. King, James Brown, and Otis Redding. Guy and Wells perform another unidentified song.
      Tape 2: Guy and Wells perform "Last Time" (blues shuffle). Johnny Shines and Shuggie Otis perform "Catfish Blues." J. Otis and Shines discuss Shines' new record, his publicity in Tuscaloosa, AL, and his work in a new movie. Shines and S. Otis perform "Kind Hearted Woman." J. Otis and Shines talk about the Robert Johnson sound, the "blues is boring" mindset, history of blues, early Black music in North and South America, and precursors to the blues. Shines and S. Otis perform "Worried Blues."
    - Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, 1971-03-22; 1 Audiotape Reel 7 in.; Featured guest(s): Pee Wee Crayton, Shakey Jake, Shuggie Otis
      EC 12914
      Live performance segments featuring Johnny Otis with Pee Wee Crayon, Shakey Jake, Shuggie Otis. Crayton (acoustic guitar), Jake (harmonica), and Shuggie (electric guitar) perform an unidentified piece, then Crayton (electric guitar) and Shuggie (acoustic guitar) perform "My Kind of Woman." J. Otis, Jake, and Crayton talk about women in blues songs. Jake, Crayton and Shuggie perform unidentified piece followed by "Green Bay."
    - Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, 1971-06-20; 1 Audiotape Reel 10 in.
      EC10 3659
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/k81j532r6b
      Otis plays the music of Lee Dorsey, Trudi Williams, Joe Jones, Chuck Berry, Dinah Washington, Clara Ward Singers, Billie Holiday, Bobby Bland, Frankie Lymon & The Teenagers, Etta James, and The Crows. Comedy segment, "Honky Tonk Bud, the Hip Cat Stud."
    - Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, 1971; 1 Audiotape Reel 7 in.; Featured guest(s): Guitar Slim Green, Memphis Slim
      EC 12913
    - Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, 1971; 1 Audiotape Reel 7 in.; Featured guest(s): Albert Collins, Shuggie Otis
      EC 12915
      Live performance segments featuring Johnny Otis with Albert Collins and Shuggie Otis. Collins and Shuggie perform unidentified song and "Glad to Meet You Blues." J. Otis talks to Collins about his old band and how Collins watched them perform in Houston as a boy.
    - Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, 1972-01-31; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.
      EC10 3658, EC10 3660
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/207t64nx3x
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of Junior Parker, Charles Brown, Nathaniel Terry, Fats Domino, Jimmy McCracklin, Elmore James, Memphis Minnie, and Ma Rainey. Otis talks about music similar to blues around the world, Elmore James's musical influences and birthplace.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of B.B. King, Roy Milton, Little Milton, Lowell Fulson, Jimmy Rushing, Johnny Otis and Sugarcane Harris, John Lee Hooker, Jimmy Witherspoon, and Muddy Waters. Otis promotes upcoming gig with Cheech & Chong.
    - Johnny Otis Show, circa 1970-1972; 1 Audiotape Reel 7 in.; Featured guest(s): Shuggie Otis
      EC10 2675
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/742930jr96
      Program excerpt featuring live performance by Johnny and Shuggie Otis. Johnny challenges Shuggie to play in various periods and styles. Shuggie improvises on guitar and Johnny occasionally improvises lyrics and sings along.
  - 4.2. KPFK (Los Angeles) and KPFA (Berkeley), 1982-1994
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, Program 1 (Rivingtons), 1982-08-02; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Joe Liggins, Al Frazier, Sonny Harris, Soupe Bradshaw
      EC10 2526; EC10 2527
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/633d96rc52
      Tape 1: Otis plays the music of The Dominoes, Bobby Day, Bill Doggett, Hank Ballard & The Midnighters, Little Willie John, Rivingtons, Joe Liggins, Lightnin' Hopkins, Jack Dupree, Amos Milburn, and Lamplighters. Otis, Harris, and Frazier talk about the Rivingtons and their new album. The Rivingtons talk about working in Tahoe; Liggins talks about where he's from, his first band, and how the song "The Honeydripper" came about. Otis and guests talk about the "Blue Monday Club." Otis, Frazier, and Harris talk about the many names they used before being called The Rivingtons, and the Rivingtons' first hit.
      Tape 2: Otis plays the music of The Rivingtons, Joe Liggins & The Honeydrippers, Ray Charles, and Stick McGhee. Live performance by Liggins, Bradshaw, Frazier, and Harris. Liggins talks about his song "I Got a Right to Cry." Otis talks about his "Blue Monday Club" and upcoming shows.
    - The Johnny Otis Show: Blue Monday Edition, Program 2, 1982-08-09; 2 Audiotape Reels 10 in.; Featured guest(s): Margie Evans, Dootsie Williams, Hank Ballard, Chuck Higgins, Johnny Turner, Koko Haynes, Don Wilkerson, Zaven Jambayzian, Charles Williams, Soupe Bradshaw
      EC10 2528; EC10 2529